A Guide to the Ford Foundation records, Publications (Non-Grant Related), Accession 2017:050 FA1304
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Ford Foundation Publications, 1
  - The Quality of Life, Henry T. Heald, President (2 copies), 1964 (Box 24, Folder 249)
    Describes Ford Foundation population program - Excerpted from the 1964 Annual Report of the Ford Foundation
  - The Painstaking Ascent, Henry T. Heald, President (2 copies), 1963 (Box 24, Folder 250)
    Excerpted from the 1963 Annual Report of the Ford Foundation - Discusses nation building and international aid
  - Ford and Other Foundations in Public Affairs, Dyke Brown (2 copies), 1962 (Box 24, Folder 251)
    A Ford Foundation Reprint from Foundation News, Vol. III, No. 4, July 1962
  - William Wallace McPeak, August 4, 1908 - March 31, 1964, A Memorial Service (2 copies) (Box 24, Folder 252)
  - Philanthropic Foundations in the United States: A Brief Description, The Foundation Center, New York (2 copies), 1969 (Box 24, Folder 253, Box 111, Folder 1301)
  - Graduate Education and Black Americans, Fred E. Crossland (2 copies), 1968 November 25 (Box 24, Folder 254)
    Office of Special Projects, Division of Education and Research
  - The Ford Foundation Program in Economic Development and Administration (2 copies), 1960 May (Box 24, Folder 255)
  - The Ford Foundation Program in South and Southeast Asia (2 copies), 1962 March (Box 24, Folder 256)
  - Ford Foundation in the United Arab Republic (2 copies), 1966 October (Box 24, Folder 257)
    Work of the Ford Foundation and grants in the United Arab Republic from 1952-1966
  - The Ford Foundation Program in Education (2 copies), 1960 December (Box 24, Folder 258)
  - Language Doors (2 copies), 1964 May (Box 24, Folder 259)
    Linguistics and language programs
  - A Program in Support of Social Science and Legal Research on Population Policy, Ford Foundation and the Rockefeller Foundation (2 copies), 1972 (Box 24, Folder 260)
  - Ford Foundation Assistance to Minorities in Higher Education (4 copies), 1971 April (Box 24, Folder 261)
  - The Near Side of Federalism: Improving State and Local Government, 1972 January (Box 24, Folder 262)
  - IR8 and Beyond (2 copies) and The International Rice Research Institute: General Information (2 copies), undated (Box 24, Folder 263)
    Reviews some of the International Rice Research Institute's contributions between 1960-1970
  - Managing Knowledge to Save the Environment, McGeorge Bundy (2 copies), 1970 (Box 24, Folder 264)
    A Ford Foundation Reprint - Address delivered before the 11th Annual Meeting of the Advisory Panel to the House Committee on Science and Astronautics, January 27, 1970
  - Language Education in Developing Countries: The Changing Role of the Ford Foundation, Melvin J. Fox (2 copies), 1974 (Box 24, Folder 265)
    A Ford Foundation Reprint - adapted from a statement prepared for the ALSED Round Table of the United Nations Educational, Scientific, and Cultural Organization in Paris, May 8-10, 1974
  - The Wages of Inflation, Roger G. Kennedy, A Ford Foundation Reprint from The Atlantic (2 copies), 1974 (Box 24, Folder 266)
  - The Art of Managing the Environment, A Ford Foundation Report (2 copies), 1974 September (Box 24, Folder 267)
  - Law and Justice, A Ford Foundation Report (2 copies), 1974 October (Box 24, Folder 268)
  - Assisting Legal and Judicial Education, Sanford M. Jaffe (2 copies), 1974 (Box 24, Folder 269)
    Adapted from remarks given before the American Bar Association Board of Governors' Task Force on Advanced Judicial and Legal Education on June 12, 1974
  - Who Administers? Access to Leadership Positions in the Administration of Government, Frank Logue, New Haven, Connecticut (2 copies), 1972 October 1 (Box 25, Folder 270)
    A survey and report for the division of national affairs of the Ford Foundation
  - Policies Affecting Populations in West Africa, A Ford Foundation Reprint from Studies in Family Planning, Davidson R. Gwatkin (2 copies) and Archives in Developing Countries: The Role of Philanthropic Foundations, A Ford Foundation Reprint from The American Archivist, Robert A. Mayer, (2 copies), 1972 (Box 25, Folder 271)
  - The Public Interest Law Firm: New Voices for New Constituencies (2 copies), 1973 February (Box 25, Folder 272)
  - Schools and the World of Work, A Ford Foundation Reprint, Harold Howe II (2 copies), 1972 (Box 25, Folder 273)
    Adapted from remarks given at a conference sponsored by the Educational Testing Service in Washington, D.C., on May 12, 1972
  - Papers on Research about Learning, Balance the Basics: Let Them Write, A Report to the Ford Foundation, Donald H. Graves, 1978 February (Box 25, Folder 274)
  - Language in Education: Problems and Prospects in Research and Training, A Ford Foundation Report, Melvin J. Fox and Betty P. Skolnick (2 copies), 1975 (Box 25, Folder 275)
  - A Foundation Goes to School: The Ford Foundation Comprehensive School Improvement Program, 1960-1970 (2 copies), 1972 November (Box 25, Folder 276)
  - A Selected Chronology of the Ford Foundation (2 copies), 1979 (Box 25, Folder 277)
    1936-1979
  - The Seminars on Media and Society, 1974-1980: A Summary and Casebook, A Ford Foundation Report (2 copies), 1980 July (Box 25, Folder 278)
  - The Ford Foundation in India, 1951-1968 (2 copies), 1968 January (Box 25, Folder 279)
  - A Survey of European Programs: Education for Urbanization in the Developing Countries, Beverly Bernstein (2 copies), 1972 (Box 25, Folder 280)
    An International Urbanization Survey Report to the Ford Foundation
  - Sowing the Green Revolution: International Institute of Tropical Agriculture, Ibadan, Nigeria (2 copies), 1970 April (Box 25, Folder 281)
  - Publications and Films from the Ford Foundation (2 copies), 1975 (Box 25, Folder 282)
  - Reconnection for Learning: A Community School System for New York City (2 copies), 1967 (Box 26, Folder 283)
    Report on the Mayor's Advisory Panel on Decentralization of the New York City Schools
  - The Ford Foundation Program in Science and Engineering (2 copies), 1961 November (Box 26, Folder 284)
  - The Ford Foundation Program in Overseas Development (2 copies), 1961 June (Box 26, Folder 285)
  - The Ford Foundation Overseas Development Program 1960, 1960 September 30 (Box 26, Folder 286)
    Excerpted from The Ford Foundation Annual Report 1960, October 1, 1959-Septmber 30, 1960
  - Metropolis (2 copies), 1959 September (Box 26, Folder 287)
  - Foundation Trustees: Their Moral and Social Responsibilities, A Ford Foundation Reprint, McGeorge Bundy (2 copies), 1974 (Box 26, Folder 288)
    Adapted from a paper originally presented at the Ciba Foundation, London on June 17-19, 1974
  - Minorities and the Media, A Ford Foundation Report, Gerald Astor (2 copies), 1974 November (Box 26, Folder 289)
  - Energy: The Next Twenty Years: An Overview (2 copies), 1979 (Box 26, Folder 290)
    Report by A Study Group Sponsored By The Ford Foundation And Administered By Resources For The Future, Hans H. Landsberg
  - Job #95-12: The Ford Foundation and The United Nations, 1982-1998 (Box 26, Folder 291-292)
    Contains correspondence and printing information regarding the creation of the publication, The Ford Foundation and the United Nations
  - Job #95-15: Le Second Demi-Siecle de L'Organisation des Nations Unies; French Version of The UN in Its 2nd Half-Century, 1995 (Box 26, Folder 293)
    Contains correspondence and printing information regarding the creation of the French and Spanish versions of The UN in Its 2nd Half-Century
  - Job #95-18A: Perspectives on Partnerships - General, 1996-1998 (Box 27, Folder 294)
    Contains correspondence regarding the printing process of the publication, Perspectives on Partnerships, as well as requests for copies and distribution lists
  - Job #95-18B: Perspectives on Partnerships - Lists, 1995-1996 (Box 27, Folder 295)
  - Job #95-20C: 1995 Annual Report - Officers/Trustees, 1996 (Box 27, Folder 296)
    Mailing lists
  - Job #95-20D: 1995 Annual Report - Letters to Congress, 1996 (Box 27, Folder 297)
  - Job #95-20E: 1995 Annual Report - Representatives, 1995-1996 (Box 27, Folder 298)
  - Job #95-20F: 1995 Annual Report - Offprint, 1995-1997 (Box 27, Folder 299)
    Includes 1995 Statement of Investments
  - Job #95-24: Jobs and the Poor, 1996 (Box 27, Folder 300)
  - Discussion Guide and Readings, Scientists at Work, Aaron Sayvetz, 1954 (Box 27, Folder 301)
    Case Studies in the Physical Sciences, Prepared by Aaron Sayvets for The Center for the Study of Liberal Education for Adults (CSLEA)
  - Forms and Forces in University Adult Education, James T. Carey, 1961 (Box 28, Folder 302)
    Center for the Study of Liberal Education for Adults (CSLEA)
  - Our Modern Art: The Movies, Ernest Callenbach, 1955 (Box 28, Folder 303)
    Center for the Study of Liberal Adult Education (CSLEA)
  - Conference Report: The Role of Liberal Arts in the University Evening College Curriculum, Pinebrook, New York, 1954 October (Box 28, Folder 304)
    A Report of a Conference of Liberal Arts Deans Held at Pinebrook, New York, October 14-17, 1954, Sponsored by Center for the Study of Liberal Education for Adults
  - Conference Report: Studying The University's Community: A Report of the National Conference on the Urban University and Community Needs, New Orleans, Harry L. Miller, 1954 April (Box 28, Folder 305)
    Center for the Study of Liberal Education for Adults
  - Conference Report: Tradition and Innovation in University Adult Education, Swampscott, Massachusetts, 1954 October (Box 28, Folder 306)
    The New Ocean House, Swampscott, Massachusetts, October 22, 23, 24, 1954, Sponsored by the Center for the Study of Liberal Education for Adults
  - Conference Report - Second Report: Evaluation of Liberal Adult Education, 1958, 1959; 1959 (Box 28, Folder 307)
    Reports of the Second and Third Regional Workshops, New York, October 17-20, 1958, and New Orleans, January 16-18, 1959
  - Conference Report: The Concerns of the Dean in University Adult Education, Chicago, Illinois, 1956 (Box 28, Folder 308)
    Center for the Study of Liberal Education for Adults, The Fourth Leadership Conference for University Adult Educators, Hotel Windmere, Chicago, March 5-7, 1956
  - Conference Report: Evaluating the Evening College as a Teaching Institution, New Orleans, Louisiana, 1955 (Box 28, Folder 309)
    Report of the Southern Regional Faculty Seminar, November 10-13, 1955 Sponsored by the Center for the Study of Liberal Education for Adults, Tulane Uiversity and Loyola University of New Orleans
  - New Directions in Liberal Education for Executives, A Draft, Peter E. Siegle, undated (Box 28, Folder 310)
  - Leading Group Discussion: Discussion Guide, The Center for the Study of Liberal Education for Adults, 1955 (Box 28, Folder 311)
  - Discussion Guide, Themes and Variations: An Invitation to Literature, Center for the Study of Liberal Education for Adults, Chicago, Illinois, 1952 (Box 29, Folder 312)
  - Patterns of Liberal Education in the Evening College: A Case Study of Nine Institutions, Center for the Study of Liberal Education for Adults, 1952 (Box 29, Folder 313)
  - Leading Group Discussion, Part III Training Guide, Harry L. Miller and Barbara Berger, 1954 (Box 29, Folder 314)
    Experimental, Subject to Revision - The Center for the Study of Liberal Education for Adults, Chicago
  - Patrioscript: Final Report Copy 2, Edited by Herbert Prescott, Grinnell College Press, 1952-1953 (Box 29, Folder 315)
    13 patriotic radio plays originally produced by the Grinnell College Radio Players under a grant from the National Association of Educational Broadcasters sponsored by the Fund for Adult Education, an independent agency of the Ford Foundation, Grinnell, Iowa
  - American Adventure Series: Programs 1-13, John Ehle, 1953 (Box 29, Folder 316)
    Thirteen radio dramas dealing with American values written during 1953 on a grant-in-aid from the National Association of Educational Broadcasters, a grant made possible by the Fund for Adult Education, an independent agency of the Ford Foundation, produced by the Communication Center of the University of North Carolina
  - The New American School for Adults, Louis K. Mather, 1955 (Box 29, Folder 317)
    Division of Adult Education Service, National Education Association - A study of how the city public schools for men and women are helping to meet the educational needs of a free society in our changing times
  - New Perspectives in University Correspondence Study, Charles A. Wedemeyer and Gayle B. Childs, Center for the Study of Liberal Education for Adults, 1961 (Box 29, Folder 318)
  - New Directions for Adult Education, Syracuse University Press, 1959 (Box 30, Folder 319)
    Proceedings: Conference of Administrative Officers and Deans of Syracuse University, April 18-20, 1958; Introduction by Alexander N. Charters
  - Cumulative Indexes: Association of University Evening Colleges Proceedings, 1948-1958 and National University Extension Association Proceedings, 1915-1957, 1960 April (Box 30, Folder 320)
  - New Directions for Alumni: Continuing Education for the College Graduate, Ernest E. McMahon, Center for the Study of Liberal Education For Adults, 1960 July (Box 30, Folder 321)
    Co-Sponsored by the American Alumni Council
  - Progress Report of Living Room Learning: A Volunteer Project, Published by The Women's Association of Cleveland College of Western Reserve University, 1958 (Box 30, Folder 322)
  - Why Students Drop Out: A Study of Evening College Student Motivations, James T. Carey, 1953 (Box 30, Folder 323)
    A Report from the Center for the Study of Liberal Education for Adults
  - Administrative Policies and Practices of Evening Colleges, Frank R. Neuffer, Dean, Evening College, University of Cincinnati, 1953 (Box 30, Folder 324)
    A Report to the Center for the Study of Liberal Education for Adults
  - Adult Education and Adult Needs, Robert J. Havighurst and Betty Orr, 1956 (Box 30, Folder 325)
  - The Changing University: A Report on the Seventh Annual Leadership Conference, Edited by George H. Daigneault, 1959 May (Box 30, Folder 326)
    A Report to the Center for the Study of Liberal Arts Education for Adults
  - A Review of 1958: Future Directions of the Center and A Report of Current Activities, 1959 July (Box 30, Folder 327)
  - Ability and Achievement of Evening College and Extension Students, Roger DeCrow, 1959 July (Box 30, Folder 328)
  - A Review of 1957: Center Activities and Projects, 1958 June (Box 30, Folder 329)
    A Report to the Center for the Study of Liberal Education for Adults - Observations and Assumptions about the Field of University and College Liberal Adult Education
  - Leading Group Discussion: Part II Supplementary Readings, Experimental - Subject to Revision, Center for the Study of Liberal Education for Adults, Henry L. Miller and Barbara Berger, 1954 (Box 30, Folder 330)
  - Leading Group Discussion: Supplementary Readings, Center for the Study of Liberal Education for Adults, 1955 (Box 30, Folder 331)
  - Leading Group Discussion: Part I Discussion Guide, Experimental - Subject to Revision, Center for the Study of Liberal Education for Adults, Harry L. Miller and Barbara Berger, 1954 (Box 30, Folder 332)
  - Themes and Variations: An Invitation to Literature: Discussion Guide, Russell F. W. Smith, Center for the Study of Liberal Education for Adults, 1953 (Box 30, Folder 333)
  - New Directions in Programming for University Adult Education, Peter E. Siegle and James B. Whipple, Center for the Study of Liberal Education for Adults, 1957 April (Box 30, Folder 334)
    Prepared for the Annual Meeting of the Association of University Evening Colleges, New York, November 1956
  - Understanding Group Behavior: A Discussion Guide, Harry L. Miller, Center for the Study of Liberal Education for Adults, 1953 (Box 30, Folder 335)
  - New Directions in Liberal Education for Executives, Peter E. Siegle, Center for the Study of Liberal Education for Adults, 1958 March (Box 30, Folder 336)
  - The Part-Time College Teacher, D. B. Gowin and George H. Daigneault, Center for the Study of Liberal Education for Adults, 1961 (Box 30, Folder 337)
  - Kitsch and U, Peter E. Siegle, 1959 (Box 31, Folder 338)
    Reprint from Food for Thought, December 1959, Vol. 20, No. 3, Center for the Study of Liberal Education for Adults
  - The Use of Print in Adult Educational Agencies, Cyril O. Houle, 1956 (Box 31, Folder 339)
    National Society for the Study of Education
  - Adult Education - A Polemic, Peter E. Siegle and Andrew P. Torrence, 1959 (Box 31, Folder 340)
    This reprint is from The Negro Educational Review, July-October 1959, Vol. X, Nos. 3 and 4, Center for the Study of Liberal Education for Adults
  - College English Association Symposium, Annual Meeting, New York City, 1955 (Box 31, Folder 341)
    Distributed with the Compliments of the Center for the Study of Liberal Education for Adults
  - Quality in Adult Education, Samuel B. Gould, 1958 (Box 31, Folder 342)
    Address to the Association of Evening Colleges, Louisville, Kentucky, November 17, 1958, Published jointly by Association of University Evening Colleges, Center for the Study of Liberal Education for Adults
  - The University's Role in Adult Education, A Journal Symposium, 1955 (Box 31, Folder 343)
    Reprinted for private circulation from the Journal of Higher Education, Volume XXVI, Number 1, January 1955 - Distributed with the Compliments of the Center for the Study of Liberal Education for Adults
  - Liberal Education Reexamined, Francis H. Horn, 1956 (Box 31, Folder 344)
    Reprinted from The Harvard Educational Review, Vol. XXVI, No. 4, Fall, 1956, pp. 303-314 - Center for the Study of Liberal Education for Adults
  - The Alumni University, John S. Diekoff, 1957 (Box 31, Folder 345)
    Reprinted from the Journal of Higher Education, Vol. XXVIII, No. 7, October 1957, pp. 353-360, 407 - Center for the Study of Liberal Education for Adults
  - The Public Conscience of the University, Richard J. Storr, 1956 (Box 31, Folder 346)
    Reprinted from the Harvard Educational Review, Vol. XXVI, No. 1, Winter, 1956, pp. 71-84 - Center for the Study of Liberal Education for Adults
  - What's Your Line?: The Task of the Adult Educator, Harry L. Miller, 1957 (Box 31, Folder 347)
    Reprinted from Adult Leadership, Vol. 6, No. 3, September, 1957, pp. 69 ff. - The Center for the Study of Liberal Education for Adults
  - Why Don't We Have Better Teaching for Adults?, Harry L. Miller, 1957 (Box 31, Folder 348)
    Reprinted from Adult Education, Vol. VII, No. 2, Winter, 1957, pp. 112-115 - Center for the Study of Liberal Education for Adults
  - Seminar on Liberal Education for Management, The Miller Group, The Center for the Study of Liberal Education for Adults, 1957 October 13 (Box 31, Folder 349)
  - Seminar on Liberal Education for Executives: An Interim Report, Center for the Study of Liberal Education for Adults, 1958 (Box 31, Folder 350)
  - Development of the Ways of Mankind Radio Project: A Report and Analysis, Walter Goldschmidt, 1953 August (Box 31, Folder 350A)
    This report is No. 4 of 26 copies. It has been prepared for administrative purposes only.
  - Notes and Essays on Education for Adults - Number 4 - Social Roles of the Middle-Aged Person: A Method of Identifying the Needs of Adults, Robert J. Havighurst, 1953 March (Box 31, Folder 351)
  - Notes and Essays on Education for Adults - Number 5 - Television and the University: A Report of the Committee on Educational Television, The University of Chicago, 1953 March (Box 31, Folder 352)
  - Notes and Essays on Education for Adults - Number 6 - A School for Optimists, Paul A. McGhee, 1953 (Box 31, Folder 353)
  - Notes and Essays on Education for Adults - Number 7 - The Liberation of the Adult, Horace Kallen, 1954 March (Box 31, Folder 354)
  - Notes and Essays on Education for Adults - Number 8 - Adult Education as a Time-Binding Process, S. I. Hayakawa, 1954 March (Box 31, Folder 355)
  - Notes and Essays on Education for Adults - Number 9 - Mass Society and Liberal Education, C. Wright Mills, 1954 June (Box 31, Folder 356)
  - Notes and Essays on Education for Adults - Number 10 - Teaching a Human Relations Workshop, Daniel A. Malamud, 1955 (Box 32, Folder 357)
  - Notes and Essays on Education for Adults - Number 11 - New Directions for University Adult Education: Institution-Centered - Faculty Organization at Rutgers, G. Stuart Demarest and The Basic Program at Chicago, Galway Kinnel, 1955 (Box 32, Folder 358)
  - Notes and Essays on Education for Adults - Number 12 - Psychological Needs of Adults: A Symposium by Gardner Murphy and Raymond Kuhlen, 1955 (Box 32, Folder 359)
  - Notes and Essays on Education for Adults - Number 13 - Schooling for Maturity, John S. Diekhoff, 1955 (Box 32, Folder 360)
  - Notes and Essays on Education for Adults - Number 14 - New Directions for University Adult Education: Looking Forward, The Residential School in American Adult Education, Royce C. Pitkin, 1956 (Box 32, Folder 361)
  - Notes and Essays on Education for Adults - Number 15 - Professional Preparation of Adult Educators: A Symposium, 1956 (Box 32, Folder 362)
  - Notes and Essays on Education for Adults - Number 17 - Adult Education in the Liberal Arts Colleges, James E. Crimi, 1957 September (Box 32, Folder 363)
  - Notes and Essays on Education for Adults - Number 18 - Liberal Education: Summary of a Discussion by the Trustees of the Carnegie Foundation for the Advancement of Teaching and Implications for University Adult Education, 1957 September (Box 32, Folder 364)
  - Notes and Essays on Education for Adults - Number 19 - Especially for Adults, James B. Whipple, 1957 October (Box 32, Folder 365)
  - Notes and Essays on Education for Adults - Number 20 - The Marginality of Adult Education, Burton R. Clark, 1958 June (Box 32, Folder 366)
  - Notes and Essays on Education for Adults - Number 21 - I Want Many Lodestars, John B. Schwertman, 1958 September (Box 32, Folder 367)
  - Notes and Essays on Education for Adults - Number 22 - Learning and Teaching Through Discussion, Ida Stewart Hill and William Fawcett Hill, 1958 September (Box 32, Folder 368)
  - Notes and Essays on Education for Adults - Number 23 - Pleasures in Learning, 1958 December (Box 32, Folder 369)
  - Notes and Essays on Education for Adults - Number 24 - Major Trends in Higher Adult Education, Cyril O. Houle, 1959 March (Box 32, Folder 370)
  - Notes and Essays on Education for Adults - Number 25 - Liberal Education for Adults Re-examined: The Queens College Program, Marc E. Belth and Herbert Schueler, 1959 April (Box 32, Folder 371)
  - Notes and Essays on Education for Adults - Number 26 - Higher Adult Education: Its Place and Its Function, Hans Simons, 1959 November (Box 32, Folder 372)
  - Notes and Essays on Education for Adults - Number 27 - A Report on University Adult Education in Australia and New Zealand, Paul H. Sheats, 1960 January (Box 32, Folder 373)
  - Notes and Essays on Education for Adults - Number 29 - Week-end Learning in the U.S.A., Robert H. Schacht, 1960 (Box 32, Folder 374)
  - Notes and Essays on Education for Adults - Number 30 - Adult Education in Colleges and Universities, A. A. Liveright; Liberal Adult Education, Harry L. Miller, 1960 (Box 32, Folder 375)
  - Notes and Essays on Education for Adults - Number 31 - Adult Education in the British West Indies, Cyril O. Houle, 1960 (Box 32, Folder 376)
  - Notes and Essays on Education for Adults - Number 32 - On Teaching Adults: An Anthology, Edited by Marilyn V. Miller, 1960 (Box 32, Folder 377)
  - Job #95-06B: The UN in its Second Half Century - Lists, 1995 (Box 32, Folder 378, Box 33, Folder 379)
    Contains Digital Materials
  - Job #95-06B: The UN in its Second Half Century - Press Materials, 1995 (Box 33, Folder 380)